本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 媚子 华青墨 Alice 日月 没有故事龙同学
校对： 唱唱反调  后期： 唱唱反调
快点 让开
Come on, get out of the way!
我要进房子里
I'm trying to get into my home.
别越线 那是我的地盘
Don't come across the line,that's my land!
嗨 斯考特
Hey, Scout!
我的儿啊 我的儿啊
That's my boy! That's my boy.
还好吗
All right?
怎么回... 等一下 斯考特
What the... Hold on, Scout.
没... 门
No... way.
你想打架 我奉陪
You want a fight, I'll give you a fight!
得了吧 艾德 走开
Come on, Ed, MOVE!
我才不怕你 滚出我的房子
I'm not afraid of you. Get the hell off my property!
你已经越界四英尺了
You're 4 feet over the property line!
我知道你在干嘛 你骗不了任何人
I know what you're doing, you're not fooling anyone!
滚出我的地盘 你个脑残笨蛋
Get the hell off my land,you half-brained moron!
救我
Help me!
# 我今早起床 #
I got out of bed today
# 对上帝发誓我看不见我的脸 #
Swear to God I couldn't see my face
# 我今早起床 #
I got out of bed today
# 注视着一缕灵魂 #
Staring at a ghost
# 你看到我的灵魂了么 #
Oh have you seen my ghost
# 感觉到它了么? 看到它了么? #
Seen my ghost, seen my ghost
# 你看到我的灵魂了么 它凝视着地面 #
Oh have you seen my ghost staring at the ground
心灵缉凶 第二季第5集
嗨 来时的交通状况太崩溃了
Hey. Traffic coming in was crazy,
由于施工封锁了两个街区
2 blocks were cut off due to construction.
不 不是施工 是爆炸
No, it wasn't construction, there was an explosion.
别太放松了 我想让你们心理分析科去调查
Don't get too comfortable, I want Psych Crimes is to investigate.
- 爆炸归轰炸队负责 - 爆炸物处理队
- Explosions go to bombers. - Explosive Disposal Unit
仍在现场 你们去那里交接
is still on site. You'll take over when you get there.
- 为什么是我们 - 艾德基诺斯基
- Why us? - Ed Janoski,
六十七岁 独居 去年因抑郁症
67, lives alone. Briefly hospitalized
住过一阵子院
last year for clinical depression.
递交过七十份骚扰报告 投诉开发商
Lodged 70 harassment complaints against the developer building
在隔壁新建公寓 开发商也投诉了艾德四十回
a condo next door. Same developer filed 40 against Ed.
- 投诉哪些方面 - 灯光 施工
- What kind of complaints? - Lights, construction,
卡车压了他的草坪
trucks backing onto his lawn.
根本上来说 这是钉子户和开发商的战争
Basically, it's a war between a hold out and a developer.
不出事我们不会干预太多
We never gave it much attention until now.
- 炸弹都用上了 - 别开玩笑了 出发吧
- A bomb will do that. - No kidding. Get over there.
现在 你只会让事情更糟糕
Now, you're just making it worse.
我没弄得更糟 我只是...
I'm not making it worse, I just...
- 他帮不上忙 好吗 - 我们先走访邻居
- He's not helping, OK? - We'll start canvassing
做做调查 从他们那儿套出点东西
the neighbours, find out what they have to say.
看看他们是否爱沙皇公寓
See if they love the Condo Czar as much
胜过爱自己
as he loves himself.
- 基诺斯基先生吗 - 是
- Mr. Janoski? - Yeah?
艾登 布莱克刑警 这是我同事克拉拉马龙
Detective Aidan Black. This is my associate Clara Malone.
一个炸弹把条子都引出来了
Every cop on the beat shows up for a bomb.
之前找你们的时候 你们在哪儿
Where were you the other times I called? Huh?
不用回答了 你们也有份儿
You don't have an answer for that because you're part of it.
什么我们也有份儿 基诺斯基先生
Part of what, Mr. Janoski?
你们得给我哥一个解释
You have to excuse my brother.
- 我弟 - 马库斯基诺斯基
- Little brother. - Marcus Janoski.
- 这里怎么回事 - 这还不明显吗
- Tell us what happened here. - Isn't it obvious?
有颗该死的炸弹在我房子里爆了
A damn bomb exploded in my house
而且他们还不让我回屋
and they won't let me back in.
那可是我的房子
It's MY house!
你们管他们叫的什么炸弹技术员的
The bomb tech, or F.T.A.,
还是操蛋部队的
or whatever the hell you call them,
半个小时前就走了 我要回屋去
left a half hour ago. I want back in!
我不能让你这么做 先生 这里是案发现场
I can't let you do that, sir. This is a crime scene.
还要多久
How long is it gonna be?
要我在大街上站一整晚吗
I have to stand out in the street all night?
不 我们今晚会找地方给你住的
Oh no, we'll find someplace else for you to stay tonight.
我不想整夜呆在别的地方
I don't want to stay somewhere else all night.
有什么进展 温蒂
What do we got so far, Wendy?
嗨 爆炸始于烟囱
Hey. Blast originated in the chimney,
从壁炉里飞出来
came out of the fireplace.
找到一些炸弹碎片 电线 还有电子零件
Found some bomb fragments, some wires, electronics.
- 专业作案 - 难说
- Professional job? - Hard to say.
一方面 他做这个花了很多心思
On one hand, someone put a lot of work into making this.
用的是旧炸药
The thing is that they used old dynamite.
看 冷凝和存储不当导致了晶体产生
See, crystals are from condensation and improper storage.
通常会引起较小且不定的爆炸
Usually results in a smaller, more unpredictable blast.
所以是专业级炸弹和业余材料的混搭
So professional level bomb with amateur ingredients?
是的 差不多
Yeah, pretty much.
用新炸药会有什么后果
What would have happened with new dynamite?
整个屋子都可能会被被炸飞
Probably would have taken out the whole house.
斯考特只叫不咬人
Scout's all ba-bark and no bite.
真是个迷人精
He's a charmer.
肯定不好受吧 住在工地旁边
Must be tough, living with all this construction going on.
我老婆的座右铭是
My wife's motto was,
"一切终将成为过去"
"This too shall pass."
真是句好座右铭
It's a good motto.
她比我更能等
She was better at waiting things out than I am.
谁是这里管事的
So who's in charge here?
- 布莱克警探 - 嗨 宝贝小家伙
- Detective Black... - Hey, sonny boy,
你该用个火力大点的炸弹才能除掉我啊
you're gonna need a bigger bomb than that to get rid of me!
-艾德... - 你想我走的话 最好
- Ed... - You want me out, you better
下次就能把我杀了
make sure you kill me the next time!
艾德 这还不是时候
Ed, this is not the time.
还有别让我看到你
And get out of my sight!
这男的很明显有神经病
So this man is clearly unhinged.
发生什么了
What's going on?
嗨 达米安特伦布莱 这是我的建筑工地
Hi, Damian Tremblay, this is my construction site.
是 我知道
Yeah, I know.
我是布莱克警探 你知道
I'm Detective Black. Do you know anything
- 这里发生了什么吗 - 他当然知道
- about what happened here? - Of course he does!
我只知道我的员工现在在医院
What I know is that I have an employee in the hospital,
还有 他的妻儿想知道是怎么一回事
and his wife and his kids are wondering how he got there.
你可以告诉他们基诺斯基的家被炸了
Well you can tell them that a bomb went off in Mr. Janoski's house.
好的 但你的人威胁说要停止施工
OK, but your people threaten to shut down my operation.
我们要跟你和你的手下谈谈
We're gonna want to talk to you and your whole crew.
只是当前我们没工夫
We just don't have time for that right now.
好啊 但我的伙计们一分钟不干活
That's fine, but my men would lose money any minute
都是在损失银两
that they're not working.
我也一样
And so would I.
你要的人就在这儿
That's the guy you want right there.
好吧 也许是他 但现在我要问的人是你
Well, maybe he is. But right now the guy I need to talk to
你愿意去市中心给我们做个陈述吗
is you. You mind coming downtown and giving us a statement?
当然不愿意
I sure do.
如果你不帮我们的话我们也帮不了你 先生
We can't help you if you don't help us, sir.
- 看好房子 - 行
- Watch the house. - OK.
- 没事的 - 来吧 斯考特
- It's OK. - Come on, Scout.
- 你不能带狗 - 我去哪儿斯考特去哪儿
- Uh, you can't bring the dog. - Scout goes where I go.
也行吧 我找个队员牵着她
Why not? I'll have a uniform walk her.
来吧 斯考特
Come on, Scout.
为什么你不喜欢狗
What do you got against dogs?
你很了解艾德基诺斯基吗
Do you know Ed Janoski well?
- 艾德真让人过目难忘 - 很明显
- Ed is pretty hard to miss. - Apparently he's had
他跟建筑工地有冲突
some conflict with the construction site?
艾德跟每个人都有冲突 他很吓人 真的
Ed has conflict with everyone. He's a menace,seriously.
自从施工开始
Yeah ever since this work started,
他住的那条街就变成了地狱
it's been hell living down the street from him.
好吧 现在是卖方市场
Well, it's a seller's market.
- 你们搬就行啦 - 要不是艾德从中作梗
- You could just move. - We would have sold already,
- 我们早就卖了 - 怎么会这样呢
- except Ed screwed us over. - How so?
达米安特伦布莱想建二期公寓
Damian Tremblay wants to build Phase Two of his condo.
我们若肯卖他会给该街区每个人个好价钱
He offered everyone on the block a sweet deal if we sell.
- 比市场价还高 - 但前提是我们都肯卖
- Well above market. - But only if we all sell.
- 是的 - 艾德连考虑都没有就拒绝了
- Yeah. - Ed refuses to even consider it.
街坊们一定很失望吧
Must've upset your neighbours.
好吧 我看不出有人想炸他
OK, I can't see anyone bombing him.
房地产 让人们失去理智
Real estate, it makes people do crazy things.
我认识的人中疯到制造爆炸的就只有艾德
Only person I know crazy enough to build a bomb is Ed.
而且 老实说 我相信他干得出来
And honestly, I wouldn't put it past him.
任何让达米安难堪的事他都会做
He'd do anything to make Damian look bad.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
对我欲罢不能 是吗
Can't get enough of me, can you?
你真是个难戒的习惯
You're a hard habit to break.
- 那是什么 - 早上你忘拿你的剃须刀了
- What's that? - You forgot your shave kit this morning.
我刚记起来 因为我花太多时间...
I just figured since I was spending so much time...
真尴尬
This is awkward.
没事
It's cool.
- 反正我在这儿要用 - 你确定
- I need a kit here anyway. - You sure?
-百分百 - 好吧
- 100%. - OK.
- 呆会儿打给你 - 前提是我没先打给你
- I'll catch you later. - If I don't catch you first.
他要我死
He wants me gone.
他用灯晃我的窗户
He shines lights into my windows,
整天钻来钻去
he jackhammers all day,
他监视我
he spies on me,
偷我的信件
he steals my mail.
你怎么知道他偷你的信件
How do you know he steals your mail?
就是因为他 我的电都被断了
My hydro was cut off because of him!
他们说我没交钱 我根本就他妈没收到账单
They said I didn't pay. I say I never got the damn bill!
你觉得这是巧合吗
You think that's a coincidence?
特伦布莱把它们拿走了
Tremblay took them.
他让整个街区的人
He's turned the...
都跟我作对
whole block against me.
别告诉我警察和这没关系
And don't try to tell me that the police aren't in on this.
你们忽视了大量的投诉
The number of complaints you've ignored!
我们没忽视这事 艾德
We're not ignoring this, Ed.
不 你们把我关在这该死的审讯室里
No, you're holding me in a damn interrogation chamber!
你还想从我这得到什么
What do you want from me?
我已经告诉你是谁干的了
I told you who did it.
你们已经有很多证据了
You already have a lot of proof.
什么证据
What proof is that?
你们可以去查我的电话记录
You can check my phone records.
他不停地给我打骚扰电话
He crank calls me at all hours.
用诡异的声音让我去死
Plays weird voices telling me to die!
哪种诡异的声音
What kind of weird voices?
就是那种电话里传出来的声音
The kind of voices that come out of a phone!
他在放录音还是什么的
He's playing recordings or something.
我没疯
I'm not crazy.
我告诉你 去查我的电话记录
I tell ya, check my phone records!
别担心 艾德 我们会的
Don't worry Ed, we will.
那是我的房子
It's my house.
我不会离开的
I'm not leaving it.
你没权利把我拘留在这
You've got no right to hold me here.
可以的时候我们会送你回家的 基诺斯基先生
We'll get you home if we can, Mr. Janoski.
如果我的房子因为这事不能住了
If my house is condemned because of this,
达米安特伦布莱要为此付出代价
Damian Tremblay is gonna pay for this!
嘿 艾德 这是我们的事
Hey, Ed, that's our business.
你离他远点 听见没
You stay away from him, you hear me?
当然
Of course.
你保护他而不是我
You protect him instead of me.
他给你多少钱
How much is he paying you?
这家伙是个偏执狂
Guy's paranoid.
- 有点吧 - 这是诊断结果
- Somewhat. - Is that a diagnosis?
- 差远了 - 就算是 也不是他炸了
- Not even close. - Even so, he didn't blow up
自己的房子 他太害怕失去它了
his own house. He's terrified of losing it.
是 他很怕
Yes, he is.
你认为他炸了自己的房子
You thought he blew up his own house?
我必须得考虑这种情况 但所幸的是并非这样
I had to consider it. But it doesn't fit, which is good.
我喜欢艾德
I like Ed.
他是个爱发牢骚的混蛋 跟我爸似的
He's a grouchy SOB, just like my dad.
好吧 这个不满的混蛋遇到了另一个问题
Yeah, well the grouchy SOB's got another problem.
- 就是我 - 什么
- Me. - What?
他刚刚用暴力威胁了达米安特伦布莱
He just threatened Damian Tremblay with violence.
不 他没有 克拉拉 不算犯法啊
No, he didn't, Clara, not criminally.
他说的气话 他没有直接威胁
He spoke in anger. He didn't make a direct threat.
我是精神病医生 艾登 我们不会等着
I'm a psychiatrist, Aidan. We don't wait for people
人们去犯罪
to go commit the crime.
如果我们判定他们对自己或他人是种威胁
If we think they are a danger to themselves or others,
并且我们可以治疗 那我们就得让他们住院
and we can treat them, then we need to get them into hospital.
艾德是个典型的处在崩溃边缘的人
Ed is a classic candidate for a break.
他所承受的压力
The stress he's under,
骚扰 噪音 现在还有炸弹
the harassment, the noise, now a bomb.
所以难道无辜的受害者被关起来
So innocent victim gets locked up
而卑鄙的开发商赢了 我不喜欢这结果
and slimeball developer wins? I don't like that outcome.
不是关起来 是住院
Not locked up. Admitted to hospital.
我肯定艾德会领会这种区别的
I'm sure Ed's gonna appreciate the difference.
他还没到那地步 但我担心他已经差不多了
He's not there yet, but I'm worried he's on the edge.
那我们得做的就是把他拉回来
Then all we have to do is pull him back a little bit.
嘿 查下艾德的电话记录
Hey, check Ed's phone records.
看看他是否接到骚扰电话
See if he's getting crank calls.
别大惊小怪 艾德基诺斯基可是头号公敌
Wouldn't shock me. Ed Janoski is public enemy number one.
没人喜欢他
Nobody likes him.
- 艾登喜欢 -他当然喜欢了
- Aidan does. - Of course he does.
那达米安特伦布莱呢 有没有什么有趣的发现
What about Damian Tremblay? Did you find anything interesting on him?
我们的公寓沙皇有使用强硬手段的历史
Our Condo Czar has a history of playing hardball.
过去的两年内
Nine homeowners have filed complaints against him
有九位房主控诉他买房时威吓房主
over the last two years over bully offers to purchase
并且通过行贿来吓走竞争对手
their homes and bribes to scare off competitors.
那些投诉后来怎么样了
What happened with the complaints?
九户人家把房子卖给他后都撤诉了
All nine dropped after they sold their homes to him.
一个月后 他的极乐境一期破土动工
A month later, he broke ground on Elysium Phase One.
现在他在筹划二期
Now he's planning Phase Two.
真希望我买了他的公寓 至少他建起来了
Wish I bought my condo from him. At least he puts them up.
两年了我还在等着搬进我的公寓去
Two years and I'm still waiting to move into mine.
挺好 他不能买艾德的房子
Nice. He can't buy Ed's house
所以他就让它消失
so he just makes it disappear.
艾德那条街上其他所有人都想卖
Everyone else on Ed's street is willing to sell.
他是唯一不卖的
He's the only hold out.
你觉得他们中会有人不顾一切
You think any of them are desperate enough
去炸了艾德的房子来说服他吗
to bomb Ed's house to persuade him?
有人会
Someone was.
我们到家了 温馨的家
Here we are. Home, sweet home.
终于 我得去看看诺尔玛的画还好吗
Finally. I need to see if Norma's paintings are OK.
- 你还好吗 艾德 - 诺尔玛讨厌任何人
- You OK, Ed? - Norma hated anyone
弄乱她的东西 很讨厌 看看
messing with her things. Hated it. Now look!
你们的人一点都不懂尊重
You people got no respect!
对不起 这是犯罪现场
Sorry, it's a crime scene,
鉴证科只是在履行职责
the forensics unit is just doing their job.
他们没必要对她的物品不恭
They didn't have to disrespect her things!
他们很可能就是故意的
They probably did it on purpose.
特伦布莱可能付钱给他们了
Tremblay probably paid them off.
- 喂 让我来帮你吧 - 别碰
- Here, let me help you. - Leave it.
- 我自己能行 - 我相信你能行
- I can do it myself. - I'm sure you can,
但我不介意搭把手
but I don't mind.
好吧
Fine.
长画笔放到这个罐子里
The taller brushes go in this jar,
短的放到罐头里
and the shorter ones, in the tin.
诺尔玛喜欢把它们分开放
Norma liked to keep them separate.
- 我能给这些花浇点水吗 - 别碰它
- Can I give these some water? - Don't touch that!
放着我来
I'll get it.
- 我回来之前什么都别动 - 没问题
- Don't do anything until I get back. - No problem.
我想知道那儿曾经是什么
I wonder what used to be out there.
一个社区
A neighbourhood.
别接电话
Don't answer that!
你好
Hello?
滚出房子去不然你死定了
Get out of the house or die.
现在就滚 否则你知道后果
Leave now or you know what will happen.
滚出房子去不然你死定了
Get out of the house or die.
现在你们相信我了吧
Now, do you believe me?
我们从轰炸组拿到了初步报告
We got the preliminary report from the bombers.
是工业级原料 复杂的电子设备
It's industrial grade material, complicated electronics.
但有趣的是 事实上炸弹
But here's the interesting thing. The bomb was actually
是被安在房顶的烟囱顶上的
planted on the top of the chimney, on the roof.
我们找到了一个支架
We found a bracket,
认为炸弹在前几天夜里的大雨中滑了出来
figure the bomb slipped out in the heavy rainfall the other night.
我们确定支架就是为炸弹建的吗
Are we sure that bracket was built for that bomb?
实验室说是的 也就是说他们只想
The lab says yes, which means they just wanted to blow up
把烟囱炸了 并不想杀艾德
the chimney. They weren't looking to kill Ed.
他们只想毁坏房子
They just wanted to damage the house.
因为这事的重点就是要把房子拆了
Because the whole point is to tear the houses down.
查到什么有关骚扰电话的了吗
We get anything on the crank calls?
做这事儿的人用的是预付费手机
Whoever's doing it is using burner cell phones.
每几天就是个新号码
Every few days, it's a new number that calls.
我们追查的号码已经没用了
The numbers we ran are already out of use.
好吧 但他还在接到电话
Well, he's still getting calls.
找到现在的这个号码
Let's find the current number.
我们在努力 你看见没
We're trying. You see this?
从艾德的监控摄像机上截取的片段识别
Footage Ident salvaged from Ed's security cameras.
这是发生爆炸的前一天
This is one day before the blast.
这应该是嫌疑人 对吧
It's gotta be our suspect, right?
不是的几率有多大呢
What are the odds that it's not?
多方便啊
How convenient.
对我来说 这很简单
So for me, it's simple.
我的工地被关闭的每一天都在消耗
Every day that my site is shut down costs money
我本来能投回社区的钱
that I could be putting back into the community.
识别显示现场已经解禁了
Ident has released the site.
你的问题与我们无关 这位是
Your problem isn't with us. And this is?
米勒温特沃斯公司的普丽娅麦克劳德
Priya McLeod with Miller-Wentworth.
我们公司代表特伦布莱先生
Our firm represents Mr. Tremblay.
城市巡视员让我们一直关闭到他们签字同意
The city inspectors have shut us down until they sign off.
你可以向他们保证我们的工地是安全的
You could assure them that the site is safe.
我是说 若基诺斯基先生能住在他的房子里
I mean, if Mr. Janoski can live in his house,
那当然我也能施工
certainly, I can work on my site.
不好意思 我需要问特伦布莱先生几个问题
Excuse me, I need Mr. Tremblay for questioning.
他是炸弹案的重要证人
He's a material witness in a bomb case.
这已经没他事了
He's done here.
特伦布莱先生很忙的
Mr. Tremblay has a very busy schedule...
不不 没事的 我想尽力帮忙
No, no, it's fine, I want to help out any way I can.
其实 我想这事我就不需要你了
In fact, I don't think I need you for this.
不如你继续向克莉格拉督察申诉我们的案子
Why don't you keep pleading our case with Inspector Caligra?
- 我应该去的 - 我宁愿你待在这
- I should come. - I'd prefer otherwise.
我是来协作的 我想布莱克警探能越快结案
I'm here to cooperate, and I think the sooner Detective Black
对大家就越好
closes the case, the better it's going to be for everybody.
这边走
This way.
哼
Hmm!
他应该比这聪明吧
He's supposed to be smarter than that.
不 他很聪明 只是混蛋罢了
No, he's smart enough. He's just a jerk. Ha!
可能吧 但不是他你也穿不上普拉达
Maybe so, but it's guys like that that keep you in Prada.
媚上欺下的主管 忍受不了
Kiss up, kick down. Can't stand the type.
即使是游戏 我也可以讨厌玩家
I know it's the game, but I can still hate the player.
或许你站错了边
Maybe you're playing for the wrong team.
我应该讨好你的
I'm supposed to be buttering you up,
- 争取到你 - 我不轻易动摇
- winning you over. - I don't get won over.
让我试试 有机会共进晚餐
Let me try. Any chance you're free for dinner?
你不会以为我想花一晚上
You think I want to spend my evening
听你为特伦布莱先生的案子做辩护吧
listening to you plead Mr. Tremblay's case?
哈哈 不会的
Ha! Ha! No, not a chance.
我在挑逗你
I'm hitting on you.
别故作腼腆
Oh, don't play coy,
我猜这种情况多有发生
I suspect it happens a lot.
问题是 你的顾客让你和我调情
The problem is, your client makes hitting on me
产生利益冲突
a conflict of interest.
嘿 我是麦克劳德 我要从特伦布莱辞职
Hey, it's McLeod. I'm resigning from the Tremblay account.
我发现它跟另一个案子...
Well, I discovered that I have a conflict with...
有点冲突
another case.
把他交给亨德森
Give him to Henderson.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding me.
利益冲突解决了
Conflict of interest solved.
多谢你配合
Appreciate your time.
没问题 警探
Not a problem at all, Detective.
那我能为你做什么
So what can I help you with?
告诉我你的保全工作
Tell me about your security.
我觉得他们是市里最好的
I think that my security is the best in the city.
有人在过去几晚上
Did anyone see or report anything odd
看到或听到奇怪的事情
in the last couple of nights?
没有吧 我不知道
Nah, not to my knowledge.
所以说 没人看到这个
So, no one saw this?
他在基诺斯基先生的房子周围窥视
He was creeping around Mr. Janoski's house.
我们认为他最后去了屋顶
We think he ended up on the roof.
非常容易被你的保安看到
Would've been easy for your security to spot.
我能说什么呢
What can I say?
我雇人看守我的地盘 而不是基诺斯基先生的
My guys are paid to watch my place, not Mr. Janoski's.
所以你的保安没有看到任何人在他房子周围
So your security doesn't see anyone around his house
或者是第二天爆炸摧毁了唯一一个阻拦你
and the next day a bomb goes off in the home of the only person
第二期公寓计划发展的人的房子
blocking Phase Two of your condo development.
挺幸运的 不是吗
It's a bit of luck, isn't it?
我是建造家园的
I'm in the business of building homes,
布莱克警探 而不是炸毁它们
Detective Black, not bombing them.
你可以离开了 特伦布莱先生
You're free to go, Mr. Tremblay.
但是我有可能需要再找你谈话
But I may need to speak with you again.
随时奉陪 警探
Anytime, Detective.
人们认为如果用现金买一次性手机
People think if they buy
我们就不能追踪到
a disposable phone for cash, we can't trace it.
但是他们错了
But they're wrong.
我们越来越近了
OK, we're getting close.
好惊讶 居然在特伦布莱建筑工地
Surprise, surprise. Tremblay's construction site.
不 显然不是
No, apparently not.
我们十二点回来 妈妈
We'll be back by 12, Mom.
哈里森先生 帕克斯顿女士
Mr. Harrison, Ms. Paxton,
- 这是布莱克警探 - 嗨 有什么事吗
- this is Detective Black. - Hi, can I help you?
我们来这是为了艾德基诺斯基 他最近接到了
We're here about Ed Janoski. He's been receiving
大量骚扰电话
a large number of crank phone calls.
我们追踪号码到一部一次性手机
We traced the number to a disposable mobile phone
- 到这个地点 - 你不会碰巧知道
- located at this address. - You wouldn't happen
关于它的任何事 对吗
to know anything about that, would you?
对不起 我们不知道
No, I'm sorry, we don't.
大卫哈里森
David Harrison
杰西卡帕克斯顿 你们因为刑事骚扰被捕
and Jessica Paxton, you're under arrest for criminal harassment.
诺尔玛
Norma?
诺尔玛... 是你吗
Norma... is that you?
# 今晚我倍感孤独 #
I'm so lonely tonight
# 如果能再拥抱你一次多好 #
If I could only hold you once more
# 如果能再亲吻你一次多好 #
If I could only kiss you once more
你觉得怎么样
How do you like it?
# 如果我能再见你 #
If I could only see you
# 只要再一眼 再一眼 #
One more time, one more time
# 哦 #
Oh, whoa-oh
# 让你看到我很爱你 #
I'd make you see I love you somehow
# 如果能再见到你多好 #
If I could only see you
# 今晚我倍感孤独 #
I'm so lonely tonight
这不可能是一场意外
There's no way this was an accident.
- 你能证明吗 - 我会的
- Can you prove it? - I'll prove it.
- 你个人意气用事了 - 这就是私人恩怨
- You're taking this personally. - It is personal.
特伦布莱知道我在办这件案子 他还耍花招
Tremblay knows I'm working this case and he pulls a stunt
哦 这是一场意外 是的 这是私人恩怨
like this? Oops, it was an accident. Yeah, it's personal.
你们什么时候离开我家
How long before you clear out?
我要一个人呆一会儿 多谢 斯考特 坐下
I'd like some time alone, thank you very much. Sit, Scout.
你不能在这里 艾德 他们告诉过你了
You can't stay here, Ed. They already told you.
我不要和你一起 路西尔讨厌斯考特
I'm not staying with you. Lucille hates Scout.
- 她会过敏 - 我们可以替你找个地方
- She's allergic! - We can find you a place
让你带着狗
that takes dogs.
我们排查好之前 你不能住在这里 艾德
You can't be here, Ed, not till we clear this up.
好吧 要多久
Well, how long's that going to take?
多久
How long?
还不清楚 对不起
I don't know. I'm sorry.
拜托 艾德
Come on, Ed.
我们在今天结束前需要钢筋到位
We need the rebar in and that next level of concrete poured
下一层混凝土浇好 谢谢
by the end of the day. Thanks.
特伦布莱先生
Mr. Tremblay?
警探 放心吧
Detective! Rest assured,
我的保险公司已经在调查此事件
My insurance is already looking into this incident.
我们没有所谓的事件
We don't have an incident,
我们有个模式 当时谁在操作起重机
we have a pattern. Who was operating the crane?
是个新人 不熟悉我的机器
New guy. Not very familiar with my equipment.
他是个合约工 都算不上是职工
He's a contractor, he's not even an employee.
可能我们需要带你所有成员回市中心
Guess we'll have to bring your whole crew downtown.
看起来你又要关门了
Looks like you're shut down again.
- 多久 - 不好说
- How long? - Hard to say.
滚出房子不然就去死
Get out of the house or die.
现在不走 你知道会发生什么的
Leave now or you know what will happen.
我们从艾德的语音信箱里得到这些
We got this off of Ed's voicemail.
你每天打给他三十次
You called him 30 times a day
在过去的两个月里面
for the past...2 months?
- 这肯定是个误会 - 我们有足够证据
- This has to be a mistake. - There's enough here
指控你刑事骚扰
to convict you of criminal harassment
并且发出死亡威胁 最少的刑罚是九十天
and uttering death threats. Minimum sentencing is 90 days.
太疯狂了 对吧 杰西
This is crazy. Right, Jess?
我们有搜查证来搜查
We have a search warrant for your credit
你们的信用卡和负债记录
and debit card records.
我们能够找到什... 杰西卡
What are we going to find... Jessica?
好吧 我们应该找个律师谈谈
OK, we should talk to a lawyer.
戴夫 这个男人是疯子
Dave, the man is nuts.
他听不进道理 你自己都这么说
He doesn't listen to reason, you've said it yourself.
- 杰西 - 这不对
- Jess. - It's not right.
我们有个机会住在更好的房子里却不能
We have a chance to live in a better house and we can't,
就因为艾德除了他自己谁也不在乎
because Ed doesn't care about anyone but himself.
里奥 帮我拿下文件
Leo, can you bring me the file?
这是你吗 杰西卡
Is this you, Jessica?
杰西 这是你的连帽衫 发生了什么事
Jess, that's your hoodie. What's going on?
如果你对我说谎
If you're lying to me,
那是犯罪 你会因此被起诉
that's a crime. And you can be charged with it.
这是你吗
Is this you?
他让我们的生活面临风险
He is putting our lives at risk.
单是对我心理健康的损害
The toll on my mental health alone...
你的心理健康
Your mental health?
在你隔壁住着一个孤苦无依的老人人
You're living beside a man who is suffering alone.
他差一点就进了医院
He's this close to ending up in a hospital, and then
然后在养老院度过余生 而你在干什么
a group home for the rest of his life. And what are you doing?
是呀 我也担心你的心理健康
Yeah, I'm worried about your mental health.
艾德家的事不是意外
The accident at Ed's was no accident.
按规矩你要先敲门 请照办
Protocol is you knock first. Respect it.
什么
What?
- 特伦布莱是主谋 - 你能证明吗
- Tremblay ordered it. - You can prove that?
我已经控制了那个起重机操作员 他快要招了
I've got the crane operator in holding. He's ready to break.
那你就有了一个刑事毁坏案件
So you've got property damage
和一个可能的民事案件 但是工地事故
and probably a civil case, but the construction accident
没有任何价值 我们要针对炸弹起诉
isn't worth anything. We need to lay charges on the bomb.
他们是同一件事 这里面可能有阴谋
It's all part of the same thing. We might have conspiracy.
打住 我不想听到阴谋一词 艾登
Stop it. I don't want conspiracy, Aidan.
给我找到那个放炸弹的人
Get me the person who set off the bomb.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我打断了什么吗
Am I interrupting?
- 没有 - 很好
- Not at all. - Great.
你准备要走了
You ready to go?
还有其他事吗
Is there anything else?
没事了 谢谢
All good. Thanks.
他是谁 前男友
So who's that? An ex?
可比这复杂多了
Way more complicated than that.
视野不错
Beautiful view.
我才不喜欢住这么高
If you like construction cranes.
早上我们会来看你的
We'll check on you in the morning.
基诺斯基先生 睡个好觉
Sleep tight, Mr. Janoski.
我们来吃点东西
Let's get you something to eat.
够了 我不想你...
That's enough. I don't want you...
等一下
Stay.
猜猜我是谁 十次猜错了九次哦
Ten guesses and the first nine are wrong.
呃... 里奥
Uh... Leo?
你觉得我的手像男人那样粗糙
You think I have man hands?
- 里奥的手很细滑 - 噢
- Leo has very soft hands. - Oh.
你想吃晚餐了吗  我刚收拾好
You want to grab dinner? I'm just packing up.
不行 我已经跟一个...
Can't. I got a date...
监视货车有约了
with a surveillance van.
- 整晚吗 - 有可能 还不太确定
- All night? - Could be. We're waiting on a buy.
- 嗯... - 但很有可能提前回来
- Hmm... - But maybe it'll happen early.
如果回来早的话我来找你
I'll swing by if it does.
开门时轻点
Open door policy.
等一下
Just a sec!
- 督察 - 现在
- Inspector? - Right now,
我是戴安
I am Diane.
你是打出租车过来的吧
Please tell me you took a taxi over here.
我虽然喝醉了 但我不傻
I'm drunk, I'm not stupid.
我给你拿点水
I'll get you some water.
我喜欢这里的布置
I love what you've done with the place!
真是舒适自在
It's homey, homie.
你让我... 让我舒适自在
You're my... you're my homey homie.
发生什么事了
What is going on?
是...
Well, it's...
两瓶酒
Two bottles of wine.
晚餐 交谈
Dinner, talking,
然后我们亲吻了
and we kissed.
- 跟达米安的律师吗 - 不是
- Damian's lawyer? - Nope.
她甩了他 他不是客户
She dropped him. He's not a client.
毫无利益冲突
No conflict of interest.
但是我只是...
But I just...
我认为不太...
I didn't think...
这很好
This is good.
很好 然后呢
Good and?
我只是有点混乱
I'm just kind of messed up.
我看得出来
I can see that.
嗯... 好了
Mmm... Ha! Ha! OK.
好了 真是有趣
OK, that was interesting.
来的太及时了
Saved by the door.
等一下
Just a second.
- 嗨 - 嗨 陌生人
- Hey. - Hey, stranger.
- 你还没睡吗 - 是啊
- You're up? - Yeah.
来的不是时候吗
Is this not a good time?
额...
Uh...
你认识克莉格拉督察吗
You know Inspector Caligra?
不认识克莉格拉督察
No knowing Inspector Caligra.
- 不是个好主意 - 你知道吗
- Not a good idea. - You know what?
没事 我要回车上了
It's OK. I gotta get back
我只是抽几分钟休息一下
to the van. I just grabbed a few minutes on break.
她刚过来 她喝醉了
She just came by, she's drunk,
她很混乱 你知道的 我们只是朋友
she's all messed up. We're just friends, you know.
不用解释
It's all good.
斯考特 早上好
Morning, Scout.
我的宝贝在哪
Where's my boy?
快点 起床了
Come on. Up and at 'em.
我们得回家了
We got to get home.
嗨 斯考特
Hey, Scout.
斯考特
Scout?
Scout!
你个混蛋
You sick bastard!
- 喔 住手 喔 - 是你杀了我的狗
- Ah! Oh, stop! Ah! - You killed my dog?!
你杀了我的狗 你杀了我的狗
You killed my dog! You killed my dog!
艾德 你不会被起诉的 好吗
You're not going to be charged, OK, Ed?
我们知道你压力一直很大
We all know you've been under a lot of stress.
马龙先生会给你做个评估
So Dr. Malone is gonna give you an evaluation.
坐下
Take a seat.
这是标准流程
It's standard protocol,
但是我们需要你的合作
but we're going to need you to cooperate.
好了 可以解开手铐了 我会带他回去的
It's OK, you can uncuff him, I'll take him from here.
这会让你好受些
This is gonna help you get better.
你不会在这里待太长时间的 好吗
And then you won't be here too long, OK?
我晚点来看你
I'll see you later.
艾德 早上好
Good morning, Ed.
我有一些问题要问你
I need to ask you some questions
来决定你的医药和财政能力
to determine your medical and financial capacity.
你有权上诉任何决定
You have the legal right
你明白了吗
to appeal any decision. Do you understand that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道你心里清楚
I know you understand.
你是一名斗士
You're a fighter.
你明白的 不是吗
You understand, don't you?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道
Do you understand the condition
你现在面临的处境吗
for which you are being treated?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道今天是几号吗
Do you know what today's date is?
艾德 拜托
Please, Ed...
跟我说说
give me something.
好吧 那我们说说经济能力
OK, I'll move on to financial capacity.
你知道欠债不还是什么后果吗
Do you understand what happes when you don't pay your bills?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果你向银行贷款十万美金
If you borrow $100000 from the bank
你无法偿还 银行会怎么做
and you can't pay it back, what will the bank do?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们在做评估
We're doing an evaluation.
你要明白 他可能丧失资格
You need to understand, he may lose capacity.
什么叫
What do you mean
"丧失资格"
"lose capacity"?
艾德...
Ed...
好像不知道
doesn't seem to know
他管理财政或健康的基础
the basics of managing his finances or health.
如果他自己无法决定
If he can't function on his own,
我只能宣布他弃权
then I have to declare him incapable.
你有授权书吗
Do you have power of attorney?
我试过了 他是不会签的
I tried. He wouldn't sign one.
你愿意以代理人的身份来接手吗
Would you be ready to take over as a substitute decision maker?
你得觉得他的治疗
You'd have to make decisions about his treatment.
当然 还要经营他的财产
And run his finances, of course.
他一直都很照顾我
He's always taken care of me.
告诉实验室赶快对狗粮进行检验
Tell the lab to put a rush on that dog food.
我们今天就要结果 不要等到明天
Let's get it today, not tomorrow.
他真该卖了这个累赘
He should just sell this dump.
以现在提供给他的 他可以过上更好的生活
He could afford a nice life with what he's being offered.
艾德在这里已经四十年了
Well, Ed's been here 40 years.
要是他离开的话 他要靠什么为生
If he leaves, what's he going to live for?
无论是谁做的 他们不会善罢甘休的
Whoever's doing this is stubborn. They're not gonna stop.
除非把艾德弄出来
Not until they get Ed out.
你昨天穿的就是这套衣服吧
Weren't you wearing those clothes yesterday?
怎么啦 你有检查我的衣橱吗
What? You're tracking my wardrobe?
布劳尔
Brauer?
他的朋友们现在在凶案组吗
His buddies in Homicide now?
不关他们的事
It's not their business.
心理战术
Tactical.
你知道他是疯子 对吗
You know he's a Habs fan, right?
哈 是啊
Ha! Yeah.
并且他结婚了
And he's married.
他已经分居了
He's separated.
艾登 我喜欢他
I like him, Aidan.
好了吗
OK?
我们能不说了吗
Can we stop now?
是的 特伦布莱
Yes. Tremblay.
我现在在工地了
I'm at the site right now.
你要告诉我为何我没看到地基吗
You want to tell me why I'm looking at no foundation?
我的人都在这里干坐着
I got guys sitting here doing absolutely nothing.
- 没开玩笑 - 嘿 给我接交通部
- Seriously. - Hey, gimme traffic.
是的 我这有个疑犯
Yeah, I got a suspect. Vehicle licence
车牌照是AZOP-607
Alpha Zulu Delta Papa 6-0-7.
给我安排一个警员在接下来的几天盯牢它
I want a uniform on it solid for the next couple of days.
我想在周末抓捕这个家伙
I want this guy out of points by the weekend.
- 谢谢 - 你在做什么
- Thank you. - What are you doing?
特伦布莱是生意人 我只是按照他的方式做事
Tremblay's a businessman. I'm just speaking his language.
把他要做的所有项目列个单子
Get a list of every project he's got going
然后寄给督察
and send inspectors to all of them.
- 什么类型的督察 - 所有我们有的
- What kind of inspectors? - Every kind we got.
嗨 波比
Hey, Poppy.
医院里的日子不好过吧
Tough time at the hospital?
不幸的是
Sad thing is
艾德说对了 所有人都想整他
Ed's right about everyone being out to get him.
唯一支持他的人是他弟弟
The only person on his side is his brother.
我刚从实验室拿回报告
I just got the results from the lab.
艾德狗狗的食物里掺入了工业除草剂
Ed's dog food was laced with a commercial-grade herbicide.
瞧见没
See?
所有人都想整他
Everyone's out to get him.
好消息是
Good thing for us:
这种东西在嘉纳泰尔里买不到
You can't buy this stuff at Canadian Tire.
Canadian Tire 加拿大大型民生生活用品连锁店
怎么了 波比
What's up, Poppy?
艾德的狗被除草剂害死了
Herbicide killed Ed's dog.
什么类型的除草剂
What kind of herbicide?
"2 4-D 胺500" 只做商品出售
"2, 4-D Amine 500." Only sold commercially.
- 卖给谁 - 高尔夫球场
- To who? - Golf courses,
- 城市公园 — 园艺师
- city parks departments. - Landscapers?
对
Yeah.
再读一遍
Read it to me again.
2 4-Delta的D 胺500
2,4-D as in Delta.Amine 500.
我们需要一张搜查令
We need a search warrant.
看样子你终于买了艾德的房子
So you finally bought Ed's house.
马库斯基诺斯基已经要坦白了
Marcus Janoski is ready to talk.
您来做这件事
Aren't you just a little bit overqualified
是不是有些大材小用啊 督察
to do this, Inspector?
我知道你的律师团
I know your legal team.
你们准备玩狠的 我们也一样
You're going to bring in the big guns, so are we.
哼 我还没请律师呢
Ha! I haven't even asked for a lawyer yet.
哦 这还用问
Oh! No doubt.
这样你就可以声称被胁迫或者虐待
So you can claim that you were coerced or mistreated.
我想你已经有了主意
I'm sure you have options in mind.
我什么都没做错
I've done nothing wrong.
是么
Really?
基诺斯基被逼疯了终于离开了他的房子
Janoski gets gaslighted out of his house,
而你正持有一份合同
and you're standing there with a contract,
准备趁虚而入 你认为陪审团会怎么看
ready to pounce. How's a jury going to see that?
我有权购买它的所有权
I had every right to purchase this property.
马库斯找上门来让我买这个房子
Marcus contacted me to sell the house.
而且那场爆炸与我毫无关系
And I had nothing to do with the bomb.
你签了这个合同你就有了动机
When you signed this contract, you gave yourself motive,
特伦布莱先生 你的处境可不太好呢
Mr. Tremblay. You are in a very bad place here.
你想要什么
What do you want from me?
我只不过买了处房产
All I did was purchase a property.
我想让你通过商业的角度理解这个问题的实质
I want you to understand the context from a business perspective.
你将面临长达数月的诉讼
You're facing months in court,
打官司的费用 更不用提
legal fees. Oh, not to mention
所有调查员和违规条款
all the inspectors and code violations
都会同时像雨点般砸向你的建筑工地
that will rain down on your building site in the meantime.
哈 这... 这将会是
Ha! This...this is going to be
你买的最贵的一所小破屋
the most expensive little shack you ever bought.
满意了么
Are you satisfied?
差不多了
Getting there.
你为什么会安置炸弹
Why did you plant the bomb?
我才不会那么做
That's the last thing I would do.
我们在你工作的地方找到的炸药
The dynamite we found
和法医鉴定报告相符合
in your place of business matches our forensics report.
否认是没用的了 马库斯
There's no point in denying it, Marcus.
你想杀你的亲哥哥
You tried to kill your own brother.
不 绝不
No. Never.
那个炸弹本不会害死任何人的
That bomb was never gonna kill anybody.
所以我用了老式炸药
That's why I used the old dynamite.
本来是想要造成最小伤害
It was just supposed to cause minor damage, that's all.
所以我把它放在烟囱里
That's why I put it in the chimney.
你根本没想伤害他 你只是想...
So you didn't want to hurt him, you just wanted to...
把他逼疯
make him crazy?
你知道什么真正的疯么
You wanna know what's crazy?
我父母过世的时候
When my parents died,
他们把房子留给了艾德
they left Ed the house,
只留给我他们的毕生积蓄
and me, their life savings
九千美元
of $9000.
这怎么可能公平
How is that fair?
有什么收获
What did you get?
那所房子 而且他要支付维修费用
The house. And he is going to pay damages.
- 不错 多谢 - 客气
- Good. Thank you.- Pleasure.
嗨 艾登 关于昨晚...
Hey, Aidan? About last night...
哦 我早早就上床了
Yeah, I went to bed early.
读了本书 是个很平静的夜晚
Read a book. It was a quiet night.
你呢
How about you?
和你差不多 呆在家里
Pretty much the same. Just stayed in.
你应该出去走走 享受生活
You should get out. Have a life.
抽空吧
One of these days.
艾德 你生气没关系的
Ed, it's OK to be angry.
别开玩笑了 我是很生气... 夏洛克
No kidding, I'm angry... Sherlock.
我连自己亲弟弟都不能信了 还能信谁呢
You can't trust your own brother, who can you trust?
信你自己 艾德 马库斯想把你逼疯
Yourself, Ed. Marcus tried to push you
可别让他得逞
over the edge into a breakdown. Don't let him win.
他已经把我逼疯了 我都住院了 不是吗
He already did! I'm in a hospital, aren't I?
已经准备好开庭了 基诺斯基先生
The board is ready for us, Mr. Janoski.
律师 你们可能会把我关在这儿一辈子
Lawyers. You'll probably get me locked up in here
- 我不去 - 再给我们几分钟时间
- for years. I'm not going! - Just give us a minute.
艾德 你要去参加那个听证会
Ed, you're going to go into that hearing
告诉他们那房子是属于你的
and show them that you belong in your own house.
没人能帮你做这件事
No one can do that for you.
我知道你很清楚自己的经济状况
I know that you understand your finances perfectly well.
你的确可能需要些小小的帮助
You might need a little bit of help,
但是你不必呆在医院里了
but you don't need to be in a hospital.
诺尔玛不会想让你呆在这里的
Norma wouldn't want you here.
你能做到的艾德
You can do this, Ed.
别对我说教
Don't patronize me.
你想寻求优越感么 替别人换便盆去吧
You want to feel superior, go change somebody's bedpan.
我能照顾好我自己
I can take care of myself.
准备好了吗
You ready?
这让我想起了我和诺尔玛结婚那天
It reminds me of the day Norma and I got married.
时机刚好
Perfect timing.
希望我没打扰到你们
I hope I'm not interrupting anything.
你到底想要什么 他这是擅闯民宅
What the hell do you want? He's trespassing.
特伦布莱先生有话说
Mr. Tremblay has something to say.
我谨代表我自己和我的工作人员
On behalf of myself and my crew,
表达我诚挚的歉意
I would like to offer a sincere apology
如果我们的施工对你产生了任何不便
for any distress that our construction may have caused you.
我希望
And I hope that that
这可以弥补您的损失
is enough to cover the damages to your house.
啊
Ah!
你不必如此慷慨
You didn't have to be that generous.
是的 他是 还有...
Yeah, he did. And...
还有...
And...
我不知道说什么了
I don't know what to say.
诺尔玛是个很会说话的人
Norma was the one that was good with words.
- 那她会怎么说 - 如果你渴望什么
- What would she have said? - If you want something in life,
就去努力争取
you got to fight for it.
杰西卡和戴夫要搬到柏林顿去了
Jessica and Dave are moving to Burlington.
法官允许他们在新小区里做社区服务
Judge is allowing them to do community service in their new 'hood.
这就像感恩节 圣诞节 和我的生日一样
It's like Thanksgiving, Christmas, and my birthday...
哈 所有节日合在一起了
Ha! All rolled into one.
希望没人指望我
I hope none of you were expecting me
会请你们喝一杯
to invite you in for a drink.
或许我们该送他条狗
Maybe we should get him a dog?
这个男人需要的可不只是一条狗
Ha! That man needs more than a dog.
的确是
Yes, he does.
我安排了护士每周给他做两次检查
I arranged for a nurse to check on him twice a week.
嗨
Hey.
真出乎意料啊
This is unexpected.
但愿这不是不欢迎的意思
I hope that's not code for unwelcome.
当然不是
Not at all.
我在你家还落了别的东西吗
Did I leave something else at your place?
事实上 我在想你的浴室里
Actually, I was wondering if there might be room
是否装得下我的牙刷和沐浴露
in your bathroom for my toothbrush and body wash?
我不太想来过夜时闻起来有一股麝香味儿
I kinda prefer not smelling like musky spice whenever I stay over.
- 我喜欢 - 你会更爱这个的
- I like it. - You'll like this better.
# 他们在我窗前翩翩起舞 #
They were dancing In my window
没错 我很喜欢
You're right, I do.
# 你唤醒我对我说 #
You awoke to me and said
# 这究竟意味着什么 #
You've been wondering what it meant